本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：silmar      校对：小路     时间轴：虫不知
特效：Will      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第十三集
求你了
Please.
醒醒
Come on!
上帝
God.
慢点儿说
Slow down.
深呼吸
Just... just take a deep breath.
Do it.
好了
All right.
现在告诉我怎么了
Now, what happened?
听我说
Listen to me.
你在听吗
Are you listening?
会没事的  我保证
Everything is going to be okay. I promise.
现在听着  冷静下来
Now, listen. Calm down.
你呆在原地  等着
Just... sit tight.
我知道该找谁
I know who to call.
索尔·古德曼叫我来的
Saul Goodman sent me.
来吧  进去
Come on. Inside.
看好门
Watch the door.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
房子里还有别的毒品吗
Any other drugs in the house?
仔细想  这关系你的自由
Think hard. Your freedom depends on it.
枪支呢  你房子里有没有枪
What about guns? You got any guns in the house?
到时候就这么说
Here's your story.
你一觉醒来  发现了她  你只知道这么多
You woke up. You found her. That's all you know.
说一遍
Say it.
说一遍  快点
Say it, please.
我一觉醒来  发现了她  我只知道这么多
I woke up. I found her. That's all I know.
说呀
Say it.
我一觉醒来  发现了她  我只知道这么多
I woke up. I found her. That's all I know.
再说一遍
Again.
-再说一遍  -我一觉醒来
- Again. - I woke up.
发现了她  我只知道这么多
I found her. That's all I know.
我一觉醒来  发现了她  我只知道这么多
I woke up. I found her. That's all I know.
你报警之后  首先来的
Once you call it in, the people who show up
会是医务调查署的人
Will be with the Office of Medical Investigations.
你先得跟他们谈
That's primarily who you'll talk to.
警察可能会来  也可能不来
Police officers may arrive, they may not.
取决于他们今天上午繁忙的程度
Depends on how busy a morning they're having.
一般来说  吸食过量死亡不算高优先级案子
Typically, ODs are not a high-priority call.
没有可以指控你的地方
There's nothing here to incriminate you,
所以如果你被逮捕了  我会很惊讶
So I'd be amazed if you got placed under arrest.
不过  如果你真被捕了
However, if you do,
什么也别说
You say nothing.
告诉他们你要见你的律师
You tell them you just want your lawyer.
然后给索尔·古德曼打电话
Then you call Saul Goodman.
其他还用我挑明吗
And do I need to state the obvious?
我没来过这儿
I was not here.
去换件长袖衬衫
You put on a long-sleeved shirt
把胳膊上这些针孔都遮住
And cover those track marks on your arm.
倒数20个数
Count down from 20,
然后拨号
And then you dial.
坚持住  胜败在此一举
Hang tough. You're in the home stretch.
低脂还是脱脂
Do you want 2% or skim?
小沃特
Junior
是弗林
Flynn
弗林
我马上来
I'll be there in a minute.
你还好吧
You all right?
弗林  快点儿过来
Flynn, get your butt in here.
天啊  妈  爸  快来  你们得看看这个
My God. Mom, Dad, come here! You got to see this!
真的
Seriously.
什么事
What?
看看这个
Look right there.
看那
Look at that.
-这是捐款吗  -是的
- Are those donations? - Yes.
给你爸爸的捐款吗
Actual donations for your dad?
素不相识的人为我们捐了
Total strangers gave us
490美元
$490.
26个人
26 people.
弗吉尼亚  明尼苏达  蒙大拿
Virginia, Minnesota, Montana.
看看这个  温哥华  远在加拿大呢
Look at this one. Vancouver. All the way up in Canada.
都是真的钱
And it's all real actual money.
就在贝宝帐号上
It's actually right there in the PayPal account.
看他们的留言
And look what they're saying.
"坚持住  沃尔特"
"Hang in there, Walt."
"好运"  "坚持住"
"Good luck." "Hang in there."
真棒是吧
Isn't this awesome?
这很
That's...
了不起
That is something.
你不觉得应该说句"谢谢"吗
Don't you think a little "thank you" is in order?
是的  当然
Yes, absolutely.
谢谢你  儿子  谢谢你  非常非常有帮助
Thank you, son. Thank you. This is a big, big help.
安大略州桑德贝又有人捐了20块
20 more bucks from Thunder Bay, Ontario.
510美元了
$510.
你要是想向我推销东西
If you're trying to sell me something,
我就给你四个字
I've got four little words for you
"请勿致电"
"Do-Not-Call-List."
如果不是  请在嘀声后留言
However, if you're cool, leave it at the beep.
我怎么知道你是故意不接电话
How did I know you wouldn't be answering your phone?
我在路上  马上就到
I'm on my way. I'm going to be there momentarily.
我希望在门廊上看到你  收拾好行李
I expect you on the porch, bag packed,
准备离开  没有借口
Ready to go. No excuses.
先生 您可能不想看这个
Sir,You may not want to be here for this.
我
I just...
醒来
Woke up,
发现了她
And I found her.
我只知道这么多
That's all I know.
她的出生日期是
What's her date of birth?
您女儿的出生日期
Your daughter's date of birth.
1982年
April...
1982年4月4日
April 4, 1982.
母亲的娘家姓和出生地
And mother's maiden name and place of birth.
-我母亲  -您女儿的母亲
- My mother? - Your daughter's mother.
毕晓普
Bishop.
出生地
And place of birth?
菲尼克斯
Phoenix.
亚利桑那州菲尼克斯
Phoenix, Arizona.
这是我们的地址
This is our address.
-有人开车送你吗  -我自己能开
- Do you have someone who can drive you? - I can drive.
那么  如果您愿意跟我们走一趟
Then, if you'd like to meet us there,
我们可以完成记录和采样
We can complete the intake and take our samples,
然后您就可以做其他安排了
And then you can make your arrangements.
您需要名片吗  两位都去吗
Now, do you need a card? Will you both be coming?
难以置信  沃尔特  你得来看看
I don't believe it. Walt, you have to see this!
-40  来自特...  -特雷霍特
- 40 from Te... - Terre Haute.
是我
It's me.
你在吗
Are you there?
我想知道你怎么样了
I'm just checking in.
我们的朋友说  他认为一切都好
Our friend says he thinks everything went well.
那挺
And that's...
挺不错的
That's good.
听着
So... listen.
给我打电话  好吗
Just call me, all right?
你得来看看  我们刚刚突破1千美元了
You've got to come in here. We just broke a thousand dollars.
好  我来了
All right. I'm coming.
有些人已经认识我的连襟了  他是个好人
Some of you already know my brother-in-law. He's a good man.
医生说
The doctors say
这次手术很可能对他大有助益
This operation has a real chance of helping him.
当然了
Of course,
他们还说他们想要私人小岛当酬金
They're also saying they want to be paid in private islands,
掏掏腰包吧
So dig deep.
捐款最多的
Biggest donation
奖励一箱六瓶装自酿啤酒
Gets a six-pack of my very own Schraderbrau.
家庭酿造丝滑完美
Home-brewed to silky perfection.
捐款最少的得两箱
Smallest donation gets two six-packs.
除了知道格米是娘们外
Other than Gomie here pees sitting down,
我们还掌握到这个
here's what we know.
克里斯蒂安·奥尔特加  别名"康宝"
Christian Ortega, AKA "Combo."
上个月被未知袭击者枪击致死
Shot dead by an unknown assailant last month.
"康宝"  你们或许会问
"Combo?" I hear you say.
"这名字不耳熟  他是谁呀
"Why, I'm unfamiliar with that name.
诺贝尔奖得主吗"
Was he a Nobel laureate perchance?"
不  他是个蠢猪  操蛋的怂货
No. He was a dipshit, wannabe banger.
除了17岁的时候偷盗哥伦布骑士会会长
Now, no arrests, save for stealing a Baby Jesus
的圣婴像被捕  没有其他犯罪记录
From a Knights of Columbus manger back when he was 17.
这伙计忒不起眼
This dude was so low-rep,
从来没在我们的雷达上出现过
He never showed up on our radar.
然而我为什么要提他呢
So why am I talking about him?
谁知道
Anyone?
布勒
Bueller?
-他贩的是"蓝天"  -对了
- He was dealing Blue Sky. - That's right.
我们见过的最纯  制作最专业
How is it that the purest, most professional grade
的冰毒怎么会
Of meth we've ever come across
被这种货色搞去贩卖呢
Is being slung by the likes of that?
别着急  还有更精彩的
But wait. It gets better.
这个偷圣婴像的小贼中弹挂掉之后
Since Baby Jesus thief there slowed a bullet with his neck,
蓝冰毒就从镇上消失了  对吧
The blue stuff's vanished from town, okay?
整个阿尔布开克一点儿也找不到了  为什么
Not a speck to be found in Albuquerque. Now, why is that?
因为你那个海森堡或许已经落网了
Because maybe your Heisenberg's in prison.
警局说  他们认为已经抓到该抓的人了
So says APD. They think they got their man.
我知道你不信  可或许就是真的呢
I know you don't buy it, but maybe it's true.
詹姆斯·爱德华杀了凯利  没错
James Edward killed Kelly, yeah.
警局认为他就是本案主谋了
APD thinks this is our mastermind.
这话都信  你可就傻透了
You believe that, I got a bridge to sell you, okay?
-他都招了不是吗  -要不是有额外的收入
- He copped to it, didn't he? - For an extra pudding cup
他会乐意每晚都呆在监狱
Every night at Los Lunas?
你要是给他一包烟
Maybe if you give him a pack of cigarettes,
他兴许连吉米·霍夫尔都招得出来
He'll tell you what he did with Jimmy Hoffa.
我左思右想
I've been thinking.
这么高级的货
Top-shelf product like this,
是不会凭空消失的
It doesn't fall off the face of the earth.
照我看  真正的毒枭一定会在什么地方露头
The way I see it, raw talent's bound to pop up somewhere.
就像游戏打鼹鼠那样  所以我就到处打电话
It's like Whack-A-Mole. So I've been making phone calls.
地区警署  小镇警官
Local police departments, small-town sheriffs.
新墨西哥州界内没什么发现
Haven't had much luck inside the land of enchantment.
但是在州外  我搞到了蓝冰毒的消息
But outside, I've got reports of the blue stuff
德克萨斯  亚利桑那  科罗拉多  内华达都有
Making a scene here in Texas, Arizona, Colorado, and Nevada.
事实上  到处都有
In fact, everywhere
除了这里
But here.
就像是某人学聪明了
Almost as if somebody wised up,
不在自己家门口犯事了
Stopped shiting where they eat.
所以说
Now,
我认为海森堡依然逍遥法外
I say Heisenberg's still out there.
我认为他向区域化发展了
I say he's gone regional.
但他仍然在镇上
Only he's still right here in town.
加油啊  两千八
Come on, 2,800.
加油  两千八
Come on, big 28.
你能行的
You can do it.
只差30美元了  再来30
Only 30 more dollars. 30 more.
40美元  两千八百一  太棒了
$40! 2,810! Yes!
-下一个是谁  -你的人找到他了
- Who's going to be next? - Your guy found him?
他在哪儿
Where is he?
好了  听着
Okay, listen.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你让你的人接他
You have your guy, pick...
闭嘴
Just shut...
索尔  闭嘴  把地址给我
Saul, shut up and give me the address.
我不建议你这么做
I don't recommend it.
警察在这儿有暗哨
APD's been known to sit on this place,
盯着出入的人
Keep an eye on the comings and goings.
他们现在在哪儿
Are they here now?
我没发现迹象
Well, I don't see any sign,
可这才是问题
But that's the point.
警察还不是最大的麻烦
Police could be the least of it.
你可能被抢劫或者枪击
You could just get mugged or shot.
你回家去如何  沃尔特
How about you go on home, Walter?
这事我来应付
Let me handle this.
看着我  孩子  醒醒
Look at me, son. Wake up.
我没东西给你  伙计  什么都没了
I ain't got nothing for you, man. It's all gone.
醒醒
Wake up.
是我  我是沃尔特
It's me. It's Walt.
我们从这出去
Let's get out of here.
-没事  我很好  -现在  带我出去
- No, I'm good. - Help me out, now.
听我说
Listen.
你不能待在这儿
You are not good right here.
绝对不能待在这儿  听到了吗
You are not good at all. You hear?
抱住我
Put your arms around me.
你得站起来
You're going to stand up,
我们走出去  好吗
And we're going to walk out of here, okay?
我们带你到安全的好地方去  就这样
We're going to take you someplace nice and safe. That's it.
我们走  起来  就这样
Now let's go. Come on. Here we go.
我杀了她
I killed her.
什么
What?
我杀了她  是我
I killed her. It was me.
我杀了她  我杀了她
I killed her, man. I killed her.
看着我
Look at me.
你没杀人
You didn't kill anybody.
我爱她
I loved her.
我爱她胜过一切
I loved her more than anything.
说实话  我没想过仪式程序的事
I haven't given much thought to the programs, to be honest.
我想应该是
I guess they should be,
我不确定  你
I don't know. Just...
你看着办吧
Use your best judgment.
没有黄裙子
There's no yellow dress here.
都是蓝的灰的
It's all black and gray.
你上次看见她穿黄裙子是什么时候
When's the last time you saw her ever wearing a yellow dress?
蓝的怎么样
What about blue?
蓝的总比黑的好吧
Blue's better than black, right?
不是深蓝  更像是
Not dark blue. More like...
也不是
Not...
很浅
Super-bright, either.
我的意思是  蓝的就是蓝的
I mean, blue is blue.
不开叉
No cleavage.
长袖的
Long sleeves.
挺漂亮的
It's nice.
很漂亮
大哈欠  霍利
Big yawn, Holly.
我知道你什么感觉  我也累
I know what you feel like. I'm tired, too.
好了
There we go.
你把那东西关小点儿好吗
Would you mind turning that thing down or off?
叮叮响的那个
The dinging.
音量关小点儿
Just turn down the volume.
爸  这可是钱
Dad, it's money.
关吧  噪音吵到
Please do it. The noise is disturbing...
宝宝了
The baby.
玛丽  慢点儿说  我跟不上
Marie, slow down. I can't...
我的上帝  你在开玩笑
Oh, my God. You are kidding me.
当然  当然可以  哪天放学后都可以
Sure. Of course. Any day after school.
等等  让我先告诉他  然后给你回电话
Ok,Wait. Let me tell him, and I'll call you right back.
好的
Ok.
-猜猜什么事  -什么事
- Guess what. - What?
-你要上报啦  -不可能
- You are going to be in the newspaper. - No way.
玛丽有个病人在报社工作
One of Aunt Marie's patients works at the Journal.
她告诉他网站和捐款的事之后
When she told him about the Web site and the donations,
他告诉了编辑  他们要给你做专访
He went to his editor, and they're doing a story about you.
真的
For real?
他们要来采访你  带着摄像
They're coming to interview you with a photo and everything.
酷毙了
Awesome.
这意味着更多的点击
It'll mean more hits.
还有更多的捐款
And more contributions.
斯科特斯德东面
East of Scottsdale?
让我猜猜  不说是吧
Let me guess. Not talking.
没有  一个也没有
Nope. Not a one.
有什么人把这团伙管的很严
Someone somewhere's running one tight ship.
就这样  警长  是的  多谢
All right, Chief. Yeah. Thanks a lot.
你也一样
You, too.
施拉德警官  能打扰您一下吗
Agent Schrader, can you spare a moment?
是的  先生  当然
Yes, sir. Absolutely.
先生们  这位是指导警官汉克·施拉德
Gentlemen, this is supervising agent Hank Schrader.
施拉德警官  有幸向你介绍
Agent Schrader, I'd like you to meet
阿杜比宾馆的安德鲁·考夫曼
Andrew Coffman of the Adobe Hotel.
-很高兴见到你  -很高兴见到你
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
坎特纳地产的保罗·坎特纳
Paul Canterna of Canterna Real Estate.
-我很荣幸  -很高兴见到你
- It's a pleasure. - Good to meet you.
洛博罗炸鸡馆的古斯塔沃·福林
And Gustavo Fring of Los Pollos Hermanos.
请叫我古斯就好
Please, just Gus.
我得告诉你  你们那儿做的鸡真绝了
Got to tell you, you guys make some killer chicken.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
他们在做今年的投资调查
They are underwriting this year's fun run,
我想该请他们参观一下
And I thought I would give them a tour.
当然  看看自己花钱养的是什么
Absolutely. Get to see what you're supporting.
我们非常感谢你们
We thank you gentlemen.
能跟我们谈谈你的工作吗
Can you tell us a little about your work here?
好的
Oh,yes.
阿尔布开克办公室负责
The Albuquerque office covers everything
从涉毒洗钱到受控物质
From drug-related money laundering to interdiction of illicit
非法越境的所有案子
Controlled substances crossing the border.
我指导的队主要调查冰毒
Now, the group that I supervise focuses on methamphetamine,
非常不幸  冰毒问题在美国日趋严重
Which is a growing problem in the country, unfortunately.
太可怕的
Terrible.
确实如此  目前我们在本地取得了一些进展
It is indeed. Now, we've had some successes locally,
但整体上贩毒量在增加
But overall the supply seems to be growing.
然而我要说  社区宣传
But I got to tell you, community outreach,
比如你们正在进行的投资调查
Like this fun run,
是我们最有力的武器之一
One of the most powerful weapons we have.
我们可以做什么
Anything we can do.
先生们
Gentlemen.
这位是你们的探员吗
Is this one of your agents?
他是我连襟
That's my brother-in-law.
他患病了  我们正在
He's got a health issue. We're trying to...
我很遗憾
I'm very sorry.
什么病
What sort of health issue?
肺癌
Lung cancer.
很难治的
That's a rough one.
你不必这样的
You don't have to do that.
我很高兴能尽力
I'm happy to do it.
-非常感谢  -不客气
- Thank you very much. - You're welcome.
我来告诉你  我有一阵子不会来了
Just so you know, I won't be back for a while.
我周五去动手术
I'm going to have my surgery on Friday.
希望一切顺利
I'm hopeful it'll go well.
但如果不幸
But if not,
索尔会照顾你  你的钱在他那儿
Saul will take care of things. He's got your money.
他替你存着呢
He's keeping it for you.
执著不放无济于事  相信我
Lingering on things doesn't help, believe me.
努努力  专心好起来  好吗
Just try and focus on getting better, okay?
我罪有应得
I deserve this.
什么
What?
你在沙漠里说的话
What you said in the desert.
我明白了
I get it...
明白你什么意思了
What you meant.
一切都是我罪有应得
I deserve whatever happens.
该死
Shit!
他来了
There he is!
我们在给小沃尔特做专访
We're doing a feature on Walter Junior.
我们给你打了差不多50个电话
We called you about 50 times.
我以为是报纸专访呢
I thought we were just talking about a newspaper story.
我知道  可是我想
I know. But I thought,
既然能上报纸  干嘛不上电视呢
If it's good enough for the Journal, then why not TV?
所以我就去了
So I went for it.
这就是他
This is him?
这位是爸爸
This is Dad. Great.
大家去沙发上坐
Let's get everyone on the couch.
小沃尔特坐中间
I'm thinking Walt Junior in the middle,
爸爸妈妈坐两边
Mom and Dad on either side.
爸爸妈妈
Mom and Dad?
到目前为止你募捐了多少钱
How much money have you raised so far?
六千三百六十美元
$6,360.
更多的捐款一直源源不断
But there's more coming in all the time.
-真不错  -我们不知道该说什么
- That's amazing. - We don't even know what to say.
太难以置信了
It's been incredible.
从你和其他人
Judging from the things you and other folks
写的材料上看
Have written about him,
你爸爸一定是个了不起的人
Your dad must be quite a guy.
他是的  他是最棒的
He is. He's the best.
你不想失去他  是吗  沃尔特
You don't want to lose him, do you, Walter?
我们都不想
None of us do.
我们爱他
We love him.
他是个好人  对吧
He's a good man, isn't he?
当然了  你可以问任何人
Absolutely. Ask anyone.
任何人  他是个好爸爸  好老师
Anybody. He's a great father, a great teacher.
他知道所有关于化学的事情
He knows, like, everything there is to know about chemistry.
他很耐心  永远帮助你
He's patient with you, and he's always there for you.
他
He's just...
高尚
Decent,
行事永远正直
And he always does the right thing,
他也是这样教导我的
That's how he teaches me to be.
他是你的偶像吗
Would you say he's your hero?
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
我父亲是我的偶像
Totally. My dad is my hero.
这会让他睡着吗
Does that put him to sleep?
这只会让他放松一些
This one just relaxes him a little.
我们快准备好了
We're almost ready.
马上送你进去
We'll be taking you in in just a minute.
要开始了
Here we are.
放松了吗
Relaxed yet?
事实上
As a matter of fact...
我不知道这是什么东西
I don't know what this stuff is,
但它确实不错
But it's pretty great.
是啊  看起来是
Yeah, it looks like it.
你醒来的时候我们会在这的
We'll be here when you wake up.
我会看到你的
I'll be looking for you.
他们应该想让我帮你摘了眼睛
They'll probably want me to take your glasses.
对极了
You better.
你的手机呢
Where's your phone?
手机  带来了吗
Your cellphone. Did you bring it?
哪一个
Which one?
我确定他没带  妈妈
I'm pretty sure he didn't bring it, Mom.
先说重要的
First things first.
宝宝多大了
How old is the baby now?
我们什么时候能看她
And when do I finally get to meet her?
我本来想今天带她来的  但是
I was actually thinking of bringing her today, but...
她明天就满7周了
She's seven weeks tomorrow.
七周  对吧
Seven, right?
我这有
I have a...
她照片
A picture,
就在这
Here somewhere.
她真漂亮
She's beautiful.
说这话总是松口气  她也真的漂亮
Always a relief to say that and actually mean it.
疼痛程度如何  沃尔特
How's your pain level, Walter?
很低  基本上是
Very low, basically.
呼吸急促呢
Shortness of breath?
有一点儿  不过好多了
A bit, but much better.
很好
Good.
你的化验结果看起来不错
Your margins look good.
显然  我不能预见未来
Obviously, I can't foresee the future,
但即使保守地讲  我也可以说
But even conservatively speaking, I can say that
你确实给自己赢得了一定时间
You bought yourself some real time here.
我们有理由乐观
There's no reason not to be optimistic.
太好了
That's great.
That is great.
他什么时候可以正常生活
So, when could he get back to his normal routine?
他现在就可以逐步适应了
He can ease into it now.
他能继续工作或者
And can he go back to work or...
这需要再等几周
I'd give it a few more weeks.
不要搬重物
Make sure you avoid any heavy lifting
多休息
And continue to get plenty of rest.
他可以独立生活了
But he can be on his own?
就是  无需依赖他人
Just more, independent.
你们自己看着办
Use your best judgment.
这对你是好消息
That's good news for you, honey?
少了个要照看的孩子
One less baby in the house.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
谢谢  能回来真好
Thanks. It's good to be back.
上帝
Jesus.
我们很遗憾
We were all so sorry to hear...
是啊  谢谢
Yes, thanks
太可怕了
Terrible thing. Just...
你知道  我们一直挂念你
But you know, we've all been thinking about you, and...
-你还好吧  -我还好
- You've been doing okay? - I'm doing okay.
到了一定时候
After a certain point,
休假也不管用了
Time off doesn't help,
所以我想我还是在这更好
So I figured I'd rather be here,
专心工作
Focus on work.
当然
Sure.
这是自然
Absolutely.
里面见
See you inside.
真实或显示高度  2-9-9-8
Truth Or Consequences altimeter, 2-niner-niner-8.
P311  请与阿尔布开克中心134.6联系
Pima 311, contact Albuquerque Center 134.6.
J5B  请报告所处高度
Juliet 5 Bravo, ident say altitude.
J5B  收到  飞往温斯洛方向
Juliet 5 Bravo, roger. Cleared direct to Winslow.
我看我就留着胡子吧
I think I may just keep this.
你说呢
What do you think?
看起来还不错  是吧
Doesn't look so bad, right?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我去汉克和玛丽家过周末
I'm going to Hank and Marie's for the weekend.
-什么时候定的  -我带宝宝走
- Since when? - I'm taking the baby with me.
玛丽会去学校接小沃尔特
Marie will pick up Walter Junior from school.
这两天房子是你一个人的
You'll have the house to yourself for two days.
我要你收拾东西搬出去
I want you to pack your things and leave.
为什么
Why would I do that?
汉克会来帮忙
Hank has offered to help,
因为你不能搬重物
Since you shouldn't be doing any heavy lifting.
我要你星期一早上之前离开  我
I want you gone by Monday morning. I want...
我要你走
I want you gone.
能不能至少告诉我为什么
Can you at least tell me why?
因为你是个骗子  沃尔特
Because you're a liar, Walt.
还是有两部手机
Two cell phones, after all.
你手术之前
Right before your surgery,
我问你带没带手机
I asked if you had packed your cell phone,
你回答说
And you said,
"哪一个"
"Which one?"
什么时候
When?
我用了药
I was medicated.
我说地球是平的也说不定呢
I could have said the world was flat.
知道我怎么看吗
You know what I think?
我看你是不小心说了真话
I think you accidentally told the truth.
亲爱的  这事我们谈过了
Honey, we have been over this.
你问过我  我也回答了
Asked and answered, right?
之后我又一次开始思考
Then it got me thinking
思考你异常的举动
Again about all the strange behavior,
尤其是你的失踪
Not the least of which was the disappearance.
我担心的发疯  给医院打电话
Out of my mind with worry, calling hospitals,
查住院资料
Checking the morgue.
你的心理状态
Your fugue state.
那个我不得不信  不是吗
I had to believe that, didn't I?
我得找个解释
I had to find a way.
我是说
I mean...
这事上为什么要撒谎
Who would lie about such a thing?
告诉我
You tell me.
告诉我你到底以为我隐瞒了什么事
You tell me exactly what it is you think I'm lying about.
什么事  外遇  我有外遇吗
What? An affair?I'm having an affair.
你是这么想的吗
Is that what you think?
那就是我想的 对
That what I am thiking.Yes.
-最近几周  -跟谁
- For the last few weeks. - With whom?
我跟谁有外遇
Who am I having an affair with?
我猜是格雷琴·施瓦兹
My guess was Gretchen Schwartz.
你们之间一定有事
Something was going on between you.
我就是知道
I just knew.
上帝
Jesus.
给我本圣经让我发誓  只要这能证明我清白
Get me a Bible to swear on, if that's what it takes.
我没跟格雷琴搞一起
I am not having an affair with Gretchen.
我知道  我知道你没有
I know. I know you're not.
因为我问过她了
Because I asked her.
为了跟她联系上我可是大费周章
It really took me forever to get in touch with her.
她几周都不接我电话
She was ducking my calls for weeks.
所以最后我就留言给她
So I finally left a message...
你跟我丈夫之间到底怎么回事
"What exactly is going on between you and my husband?"
我想这会引起她注意  如我所料
I thought that would get her attention, and it did.
她给我回了电话  而且最后她告诉了我
So she called me back, and she finally told me.
你治病的钱
The money for your treatment,
格雷琴和埃利奥特一分钱都没给你
Gretchen and Elliott didn't give you a dime.
他们没出钱
They paid for nothing.
你拒绝了他们所有的帮助
You refused every offer they made you.
可是这不对劲
But that didn't make sense
因为我问过医院的戴尔克沃利
Because I checked with Delcavoli at the hospital, and...
不包括手术费
Not including your surgery,
我们差不多付了
We're nearly paid up.
10万美元
Over $100,000.
哪儿来的钱
Out of where?
天上掉下来的
Out of thin air?
可是之后
But then...
我又打电话给你母亲
I called your mother.
这也多谢你了
Thanks for that, too.
我当时想  或许她有笔钱我不知道呢
But I thought, maybe she has some money that I don't
或许她慷慨解囊
Know about. Maybe she contributed.
也是有可能的
It's possible.
结果不但钱不是你母亲给的  我还发现
It turns out that not only is the money not from your mother,
她甚至不知道你得了癌症
She didn't even know that you have cancer.
你根本没去看她
You never went to see her.
我送你去机场  又接你回来
I dropped you at the airport. I picked you up.
你走了4天
You were gone for four days, and...
可她却发誓说
Yet she swears...
你从没去过她那
That you were never there.
谎言谎言谎言还是谎言
Lies on top of lies on top of lies.
你能不能
Could you...
就一次
Just once...
尊重我
Do me the courtesy
别否认了
Of not denying it?
别这样  求你
Don't do this, please.
求你别走
Please don't go.
如果我说实话
If I tell you the truth,
你能留下来吗
Will you stay?
留下来  我全都告诉你
Stay, and I will tell you everything.
不管你要说什么
Whatever it is...
我太害怕  不想知道
I'm afraid to know.
W515  收到请回答
Wayfare, 5-1-5 radio check.
W515  阿尔布开克中心收到
Wayfare 5-1-5 Albuquerque Center, roger.
爬升  保持在1-3000高度
Climb and maintain 1-3,000.
JM21  4号通讯器
Juliet Mike 2-1, Squawk 4.
识别201航线
2-0-1 ident.
JM21  爬升并保持在1-7000高度
Julie Mike 2-1, climb and maintain 1-7,000.
请向阿尔布开克中心汇报航向
Cleared direct to Albuquerque via the...
飞机呼叫  请稍等
Aircraft calling. Please stand by.
JM21  转向  忽略
Jane Mike 2-1, turn heading... Disregard.
飞机呼叫  请重复
Aircraft calling, say again.
L46
Lifeguard 4-6.
请向阿尔布开克中心汇报航向
Cleared direct to Albuquerque.
爬升  维持在1-7000高度
Climb and maintain 1-7,000.
JM21
Juliet Mike 2-1,
左转朝1-1-5前进
Turn left heading 1-1-5.
W515
Wayfare 5-1-5.
飞机在三点钟方向  K  转向0-8-5
Traffic 3:00. Kingair, turn left heading 0-8-5.
SA  A请与阿尔布开克中心13
Sierra Alpha. Alpha contact Albuquerque Center 13...
4.6联系
4.6.
请与阿尔布开克中心134.6联系
Contact Albuquerque Center 134.6.
W515  下降
Wayfare 5-1-5. Descend.